PRAMIT SINGHI

Product Designer

Profile

Solve problems for users to make their experience better and learn continuously to evolve design. A good product is defined by its user's experience. Work with good research on the problem and use best present technology to meet all requirements of business.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee

JUL 2015 - PRESENT

B. Tech in Electrical Engineering

Experience

Pontoon @ Mozilla (GSoC '18)

MAY 2018 - AUG 2018

DESIGN

Performed quantitative user research to understand user perception towards homepage and redesigned and developed the homepage to

improve the experience.

Cerebro @ SDSLabs

FEB 2018 - AUG 2018

DESIGN

DEVELOPMEN

Made from scratch ML competitions hosting webapp for the college students. Made Information Architecture, Low/High-fidelity wireframes, UI style guide, graphics. Worked on the copy and front-end using ReactJs.

User Experience @ ZestMoney

DEC 2016 - JAN 2017

DESIGN

Redesigned user flow connection through the mails, using a step-by-step mailing procedure to make the process clear and easy. Worked on branding and marketing projects too.

Enroute @ SDSLabs

SEP 2018

DESIGN

Complete game designed during a two-day game hackathon. Story based designing, with graphics and sound inputs.

Position of Responsibilities

Head of Design @ SDSLabs, IIT Roorkee

APR 2018 - PRESENT

Lead a design team to create products to problems focused on students. Promote a culture of integration of technology and design. Conduct various design open-lectures and sprints to evolve design culture.

Vice President @ Geek Gazette, IIT Roorkee

APR 2017 - APR 2018

Lead a team of designers, developers to increase readers online and offline subscriptions through better reading experience and clean design.

Details

singhi.pramit@gmail.com +91-9001783237

LinkedIn Medium Dribbble

Languages

English, Hindi

Skills

Design

Illustrator, Photoshop, Sketch, Figma, InVision

Development

Atom, Git, Javascript, HTML/CSS, ReactJS, jQuery, C++, Python

Secondary Skills

Marketing Research and Data Analysis, Artificial Neural Networks, Fuzzy Logics, Control Systems.

Passion

User Research , Concept Development, User Interaction.